<resources>
    <string name="app_name">GdanskPostcards</string>
    <string name="start_btn_content_description">Start</string>
    <string name="info_btn_content_description">Info</string>
    <string name="menu_home">Home</string>
    <string name="menu_gallery">Gallery</string>
    <string name="menu_info">Info</string>
    <string name="gallery_forward_content_description">forward</string>
    <string name="gallery_backward_content_description">backward</string>
    <string name="gallery_img_content_description">image</string>
    <!-- Menu -->
    <string name="gallery_selector_header">Menu</string>
    <string name="gallery_selector_gdansk">Gdańsk</string>
    <string name="gallery_selector_gdynia">Gdynia</string>
    <string name="gallery_selector_sopot">Sopot</string>
    <string name="gallery_selector_other">Other</string>

    <!-- Picture descriptions -->

    <!-- Gdansk -->
    <string name="blured_gdansk_city.jpg">Gdańsk is a city in northern Poland with a population of around 470,000. It is a major seaport on the Baltic Sea and has a rich history as a trading hub. The city\'s architecture is a blend of Gothic, Renaissance, and Baroque styles. Gdańsk\'s Old Town, a UNESCO World Heritage Site, is famous for its charming streets and vibrant atmosphere. It is also known for its role in the Solidarity movement and offers a variety of cultural attractions and a lively waterfront.</string>
    <string name="blured_gdansk_fountain_second.jpg">The Neptune fountain was created on the initiative of the mayor Bartlomiej Schachmann and the city council. The fountain dates from the 17th century. After the end of the Second World War, the fountain was restored and was fully operational 1957 again.</string>
    <string name="blured_gdansk_fountain.jpg">Neptune\'s Fountain in Gdańsk is a famous landmark, built in 1633. It symbolizes wealth and power and features a 10-meter statue of the sea god Neptune. Originally made of bronze, it was dismantled during World War II and later restored.</string>

    <!-- Sopot -->
    <string name="blured_sopot_beach.jpg">The large sunny sandy beach, which is bordered by the Baltic Sea, allows you to play summer sports such as volleyball, as well as pleasant relaxation and well-being.</string>
    <string name="blured_sopot_boat.jpg">The pirate ship will take you on a water adventure around the port of Sopot.</string>
    <string name="blured_sopot_house.JPG">The Crooked House, completed in 2004, is located in Dolny Sopot. It is considered a symbol of the modern world. It harmoniously combines the worlds of culture and art</string>
    <string name="blured_sopot_nothing.jpeg">Sopot is one of the most famous Polish towns in the Czech Republic, especially thanks to its music festival Sopot Festival, popular in the former Czechoslovakia especially in the 1970s and 1980s</string>
    <string name="blured_sopot_pier.jpg">We are having a good time in Sopot.</string>
    <string name="blured_sopot_sea.JPG">You can sail to the cities of Gdańsk, Sopot, Gdynia, but also to other countries from Poland by ferry.</string>
    <string name="blured_sopot_ship.jpg">The Pier in Sopot is the longest pier in the Baltic Sea and the longest wooden pier in Europe. The pier is 511.5 meters long and 10 meters wide</string>
    <string name="blured_sopot_tower.JPG">Sopot is a fantastic holiday destination with sunny beaches, the longest wooden pier in Europe, and an active nightlife provided by its numerous bars, pubs and clubs.</string>

    <!-- Gdynia -->
    <string name="blured_gdynia_city_beach.jpg">Gdynia City Beach is undoubtedly one of the most beautiful beaches on the Polish coast. It is situated near the port.</string>
    <string name="blured_gdynia_dar_pomorza.jpg">The Dar Pomorza is a Polish full-rigged sailing ship built in 1909 which is preserved in Gdynia as a museum ship. She has served as a sail training ship.</string>

    <!-- Other -->
1   <string name="blured_other_siberian_path.jpg">The Siberian house was brought to Poland from Zapleskin, one of the oldest places where Poles were sent. "Sybirak" traveled about 8,100 km, through: Ust, Tashkent, Omsk, Moscow, Minsk…</string>
    <string name="blured_other_siberian_one.JPG">The Siberian House is a gift to Poles from exiles living in Siberia who wanted to remind Poles in the country that Poles live in Siberia all the time and dream of returning to their homeland.</string>
    <string name="blured_other_siberian_second.JPG">The Siberian house is probably about 240 years old. It is built from three-hundred-year-old Angara pine logs.</string>
    <string name="blured_other_szymbark.jpg">Kaszubska deska, a record board measured 36 m and 83 cm. It was 6–7cm thick and weighed over 1100kg. It took 50 men to hang it on the wall.</string>
    <string name="szymbark2">Szymbark is a small village in northern Poland, located in the Pomeranian Voivodeship, near the city of Gdańsk. It is known for its reconstructed wooden village that resembles a traditional Polish village from the 18th and 19th centuries. You can walk through narrow streets surrounded by traditional wooden houses and discover the history of the Polish countryside. One of the main attractions in Szymbark is house  which is built upside down. You can walk through the interior of this house and experience optical illusions and entertainment.</string>

</resources>